hi and welcome back to living in Central
Texas if you are relocating to the
temple B in the area for a job in
healthc care or you're just looking to
be near some of our many major medical
facilities like behind me then this
video is for you today I'll be giving
you a tour of some of our greatest areas
and neighborhoods nearest our major
medical Hub let's get started Temple
Texas has a strong reputation as a
medical hub primarily due to its
presence of Baylor Scott and White
Health the largest not for-profit
healthcare system in Texas here are some
key reasons why medical facilities play
such a big role in Temple Baylor Scott
and White Medical Center in Temple is
the flagship hospital and has been a
Cornerstone of Temple's economy and
identity for over a century it serves as
a major teaching Hospital training
future doctors and healthc Care
Professionals it offers a Specialized
Care in numerous medical Fields making
it a regional referral center central
location and accessibility Temple is
strategically located along I35 making
it an accessible healthc care hub for
Central Texas it draws patients from
nearby cities like Waco Colleen and
Austin as well as rural communities
Medical Education and Research Texas A&M
University Health and Science Center
Partners with Baylor Scott and White
providing top tier medical education the
city has research facilities that
contribute to Medical
advancements veterans healthc care
presence the Veterans Medical Center in
Temple is a significant VA Hospital
serving Central Texas veterans the
facility brings veterans from All Over
Texas further solidifying Temple's role
in
healthcare economic and job impact
Healthcare is one of the largest
employers in the region attracting
medical professionals from all over the
country many support Industries
including medical supply companies and
specialized clinics have grown around
the Healthcare System here this strong
medical presence not only boosts
Temple's economy but makes it an
attractive place for those seeking high
quality Health Care Medical Careers or a
community with robust medical
services so our first stop is in Bella
Tera in Temple this is city of Temple as
well as Temple ISD uh property taxes are
going to be around the
2.3% rate here and what's really awesome
is proximity here you are right off of
the entrance is right off of 31st Street
you take 31st Street straight up to the
to the main Baylor Scott and White
Hospital probably 5 minutes from there
you're 5 to 8 minutes from mlan children
children's hospital um 6 to 8 minutes
from the VA hospital so location if
you're looking to be near the hospitals
are is perfect um some of the builders
that build in here you have new
construction as well as resale this
community is new were but it is still um
building into additional phases some of
the builders you'll find in here are KS
Eagle Ridge Tyrion flint rock those to
me are the biggest in this Community all
of which are offering really great
incentives in this moment in time now
when people look into um communities
here they're a little leery when we talk
about HOAs I know a lot of States HOAs
are incredibly High we're talking
hundreds a month the HOA here is 350
annually really low compared to a lot of
those other places it keeps the
neighborhood looking nice and clean and
then plans for future development so
this community has plans of a future
pool playgrounds walking trails a lot of
really great amenities and close access
if you're looking to be near the
hospitals let's head on over to number
two okay second stop on our tour is a
very new community called harrick Ranch
in South Temple off of
fm93 um going out towards uh Academy so
this is slightly more rural than our
last community has a little bit more of
a country and private feel it is city of
Temple Academy
ISD and where our last Community had
homes priced just over 400,000 up to
600,000 brand new as well as resale cuz
that community's been there for a couple
years this one is brand spanking new so
most of the homes in here are going to
be new
construction priced probably 280 to 350
380 is and the builders here you're
going to find are Kila Omega and
stylecraft so different Builders
different price points tax rate here is
going to be about
2.24
currently and um again Academy ISD so
that different School District does make
a difference to a lot of folks and that
is a very desired School District your
HOA Fe fees here are about
$120 annually so almost half or just
actually under half of the last
community but there really aren't any
amenities here just yet really great
different opportunity um you are
slightly further away from the hospitals
so I'd say about 10 minutes from um
Scott and White 7 to 8 minutes from
llean children's and 12 to 15 from the
VA hospital so still a short drive just
depending on what you're looking for and
where you're looking to be let's head on
over to number three three okay our
third and final stop is in the Prairie
Ridge Community in Temple this is right
off of HK DOD and loop and Old Highway
95 just behind the Tractor Supply and
the location here is probably the
quickest of all three communities we we
toured in terms of ease uh and and just
closeness to the hospitals so you are
just a couple minutes away I think just
one exit up from the VA Hospital two or
three exits up from Baylor Scott and
White and uh 5 to 7 minutes from mlan
children's so really great there you're
also about 4 to 5 minutes from 31st
Street to all of your shopping dining
and other local amenities in Temple so
this community is in Temple ISD city of
Temple pretty new community the builders
that are still selling new construction
in this community are Cory herring in
Jerry Wright I just did a video and
toured a Jerry Wright home in the Mesa
Ridge Community in belon ISD if you want
to pop on over and take a tour of one of
his homes just to get a feel of what
they look like very stunning um a lot of
detailed work there but those are the
two builders that are still building
here and then otherwise we are starting
to see resales in this community just
depending on which route you want to go
this home behind me is currently under
contract was able to negotiate neate I
was able to negotiate a fantastic deal
for my buyers um the Builder offered 6%
towards my buyer closing costs and
concessions so they use some of that
money to pay for all their fixed closing
costs and then the additional amount to
buy down their permanent and fixed
interest rate and then we also
negotiated in a fridge and washer and
dryer so there's tons of opportunity out
there if you're looking to buy and um
really cute little Community all three
are really great this one's going to be
homes priced in the high 200,000 to Mid
300,000 price range um there are a lot
of luxury and higher end communities I
can I'd be happy to do another tour of
those at another time today we focused
on more of those entrylevel homes and
mid-range homes so the high twos to low
um low fives High fours but I hoped that
taking a look at these three communities
was helpful and before I forget I can't
believe I almost forgot I wanted to
highlight a really really awesome
financing or financial opportunity um if
you are a if you are um a physician or
if you're in profession the medical
profession in general so there is a
program currently available by one of
our local lenders that I think is being
really underutilized ized it's a a
program available to
Physicians um they've now extended it to
professions like
veterinarians
optometrists nurse practitioners and
some other fields but essentially it's a
0% down Loan program so with that
program you can do 0% down um and for a
you can you have two options you can do
a 71 adjustable rate mortgage where you
still have 0% down but you get a um
lower interest rate or you can still do
a 0% down and do a fixed 30-year rate
for a little bit of a higher interest
rate so it's a really really cool
program to look into if you are looking
to relocate here for the medical
profession I have tons of information in
terms of neighborhoods and awesome
financing opportunities like the ones I
just mentioned so if you're looking to
relocate to the Temple area for medical
whether that's job relocation or just
being near those facilities you can find
all my contact information below I'd
love to explore different Financial
opportunities um and discuss what our
area and Market looks like until next
time I'm Andrea dudic realtor and
Associate broker with Vista Real Estate
[Music]